Hi! Welcome to Opportunities.
Opportunities is a new app
for the Edovo platform
that helps you understand
your potential release dates
and the different types of release
you may be eligible for.
With Opportunities, you can:
View the release dates you currently
receive from the Legal Record Office or
your Case Manager.
Learn what different release types mean,
including the requirements and conditions
in plain language.
We also share this disclaimer to note
that this application is for general
and supplemental purposes only.
It is not intended to be substituted
for the official record
of this information.
Now, we're in the portal.
This is what you'll see.
The general structure is a homepage
that shows your release and review types,
and an explainer page with information
about what the dates mean.
The first thing you'll see is this
light gray banner at the top.
This banner shows the date
the information was last changed.
If you have any questions about
when the data will be updated,
you should always refer to this banner.
If we scroll, the next section shows
your important dates.
These are all of the projected release dates
that the Legal Records Office has calculated
for a resident's sentence.
These dates are subject to change, based on
changes to Good Time and parole denial.
We know sentence dates can be confusing.
That's exactly why each date here
comes with a plain English summary,
so you're not left guessing or relying
on secondhand information from the yard.
You may see several different possible
release or review types,
depending on your sentence.
Not everybody will have all
of the possible dates.
The app only shows the dates
that apply to you.
You will see the sentence name, the date,
the amount of time from the date,
and summary in plain English.
If you scroll to the bottom of the page and
click on the Learn More About Dates button,
you'll be taken to an explainer
page with information about
what the review dates and release dates mean.
Each link directly corresponds to a specific
explanation on the following:
What do my dates mean?
An explanation on how Good Time
can affect dates.
An explanation of credits
that can shorten a sentence.
An explanation of why some credits
don't impact dates.
Guide on how Transitional Housing works.
Information about the STEP Program.
Instructions for what to do post-release.
A "What happens if..." section to answer
common situational questions.
Information on how dates are calculated.
Information about the labels on the
Parole Board Review Date.
An explanation for individuals serving
more than one sentence at a time,
concurrent and consecutive.
And a statement to submit a kite
to the Legal Records Office
for additional sentence questions.
As I mentioned, if you click on any of
these subheaders, you'll be taken directly
to the section on this full page.
This page is very robust and includes all
commonly asked questions you may have.
If you would like to return to
the homepage, you'll scroll up and
click on this "Back to Home" button.
Ultimately, this app itself is
designed to be very simple.
Just two pages: one that shows your release
and review dates in the demo video,
and another containing descriptions
about those dates.
A few final important notes.
A banner at the top of your tablet screen will
tell you when the data has been last updated.
The app refreshes every day, but
you may not notice any changes
unless your release date has
changed for some reason.
For example, good time credit updates.
This tool will only live on your tablet.
It will only show your own information,
not others'.
It will not show information
about your crime.
The app pulls directly from Elite
and is not a separate calculation.
Thank you for learning more about Opportunities.